I am a PhD student at the University of Groningen in The Netherlands since October 2019, under supervision of Jorge A. Pérez. My research topic is correctness of communicating software, focussed on session types and their connection to linear logic. Though most of my work is theoretical, I am interested in the practical implications of my work and its feasibility in realistic scenarios. I am a quick learner and enjoy studying subjects/techniques outside my comfort zone.

During my PhD I have published several collaborations with my supervisor at workshops. Unfortunately, most of the duration of my PhD there were limited possiblities of initiating collaborations outside my department, because travel was limited due to the corona pandemic. This changed early 2022, after which I started and completed several projects with collaborators from outside my department. One of these projects has been published, several are under submission at conferences. From September until November 2022 I was a visiting scholar at Carnegie Mellon University in Pittsburg, Pennsylvania, USA, under the wing of Stephanie Balzer. Here I gave several seminars on my own work, and started a research collaboration that is still ongoing.

Date of birth 8 February 1993

Academic publications

- Oct-2022 **A decentralized analysis of multiparty protocols**, *with Jorge A. Pérez*, Science of Computer Programming https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scico.2022.102840
- Oct-2022 A bunch of sessions: a propositions-as-sessions interpretation of bunched implications in channel-based concurrency, with Dan Frumin, Emanuele D'Osualdo, and Jorge A. Pérez, OOPSLA 2022
 https://doi.org/10.1145/3563318
- Sep-2022 **Asynchronous Functional Sessions: Cyclic and Concurrent**, with Jorge A. Pérez, EXPRESS/SOS 2022 https://doi.org/10.4204/EPTCS.368.5
- Oct-2021 Deadlock Freedom for Asynchronous and Cyclic Process Networks, with Jorge A. Pérez, ICE 2021 https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2110.00146
- Apr-2020 Session Type Systems based on Linear Logic: Classical versus Intuitionistic, with Jorge A. Pérez, PLACES 2020 https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2004.01320

Education

- Sept-2017 Logic, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, MSc
- -Sept-2019 Computational track

Research projects

The process of purely event-driven programs
 Supervisors: Dr. ir. B. Diertens and Dr. A. Ponse

	 Purely event-driven programming in PSF and Go Supervisors: Dr. ir. B. Diertens and Dr. A. Ponse Curry-Howard correspondence for concurrent programming: a case study Supervisor: Dr. J.A. Pérez, Co-supervisor: Dr. A. Ponse Analysing multiparty session types in a binary setting Supervisor: Dr. J.A. Pérez, Co-Supervisor: Dr. A. Ponse
Thesis	The Logic of Fault-tolerance in Message-Passing Concurrency Supervisor: Dr. J.A. Pérez, Co-Supervisor: Dr. A. Ponse Grade: 8
Sept-2012 -Sept-2017	Computer Science, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, BSc
Thesis	Purely event-driven programming
	A theoretical design of a programming language focussed around a purely event-driven programming paradigm
	Supervised by Dr. ir. B. Diertens and Dr. A. Ponse Grade: 9
2005–2012	VWO, Damstede, Amsterdam, Gymnasium
Profile	NT (Natuur en Techniek)
	Employment
	PhD student, University of Groningen, Groningen Supervisor: Jorge A. Pérez
Oct-2016 -Aug-2019	Several Teaching Assistant jobs
	 UvA - Webklas Informatica (High school; Dr. A. Ponse and Dr. I. Bethke) UvA - Theoretical Aspects of Programming (BSc; twice; Dr. A. Ponse) UvA - Automata and Formal Languages (BSc; twice; Dr. I. Bethke) VU - Protocol Validation (MSc; Dr. A. Ponse)
Sept-2018 -Oct-2019	Independent programmer , Bas Programmeert een Beetje, The Netherlands Self-employed programming and related work.
Oct-2010 –Sept-2018	Lead developer , <i>Het Zwarte Fietsenplan B.V.</i> , Amsterdam Het Zwarte Fietsenplan is a chain of bicycle stores, involved in sale, repair, lease and rental of bikes. The company uses an intranet website to manage schedules, tickets, and many micro-management related functionality.

2010–2013 Maintaining the existing system using PHP/JavaScript, and adding new functionality 2013–2018 Employing fellow students and developing a new system using Python/JavaScript

Several spare-time jobs, Amsterdam
Door-to-door magazine delivery, supermarket stockboy, mail delivery.
Other activities and accomplishments
Studied Slavic Languages en Culture (Russian) BA , <i>University of Amsterdam</i> , <i>Not completed</i>
Chairman of symposium "Awesome IT", VIA, University of Amsterdam
Board (Chief of Education) of study association VIA (Informatics) , <i>University of Amsterdam</i>
Diverse study association involvement , VIA (Informatics), University of Amsterdam
Supervised several committees, edited the magazine, worked on the website, and several other activities.
Price for best profile thesis, Damstede, Amsterdam
Shell Ecomarathon , <i>Damstede</i> , Amsterdam Participation in race with energy-efficient vehicles, using a hydrogen engine.
Editor-in-chief of high school magazine "Drukwerk", Damstede, Amsterdam
Robocup Junior (Lego), Nemo, Amsterdam, 3rd place
Robocup Junior (Lego), Nemo, Amsterdam, 2nd place